Spas Zdravkov Spasov

Sofia, Bulgaria

00359 (0)888 989 764

spas.z.spasov@gmail.com

github.com/metalevel-tech

askubuntu.com/users/566421



Year of birth 1980, single

Resume

Computers and computer science in general have been my hobby since I was eight years old. Last year I decided to follow my dream and turn this hobby into a new professional career. I left my previous job as a management consultant, shortly after I applied to some courses to improve my skills in the area of IT.

Since then, I've completed a few JavaScript courses and several of the Cisco's NDG modules. Based on this, along with my previous semi-professional experience within the area of IT and in line with my hobby interests, I've come to the conclusion that the field of DevOps and system administration is the one where I am a perfect fit. But I also like web development especially JavaScript tasks. In my free time, when I'm not playing with computers, I like reading books, hiking & gym training.

My belief is that the world grows through sharing knowledge between individuals. What I am looking for is the opportunity to focus my efforts in the right direction, to learn new things and the challenge to solve tasks that are beyond my current knowledge.

Education

2010 – 2015 Doctor of Engineering Science in Automated Systems for Data Processing and Management Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, Department of Automation of Discrete Production Engineering.

2005 - 2007Master of Science in Computer Technologies in Mechanical Engineering Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Machine Technology, Department of Technology of Machine Building and Metal Cutting Machines.

2001 – 2005 **Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering** Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Machine Technology, Department of Technology of Machine Building and Metal Cutting Machines.

2000 - 2001Army service in Special Forces of Bulgarian Army, Paratrooper.

Specialist Degree 1995 – 1999 High School of Machine Technologies, Pazardjik, Bulgaria, Department of Machine-Building.

Languages

Bulgarian Native

Conversational English

Employment History

2019 – 2021 Management consultant, IT administrator and specialist at "Information Technologies and

Sofia, Bulgaria the Future of the Economic Science Foundation".

Positions and activities: Development of training programs and presentations of the company; Executive of trainings of the personal of the company; Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Project management; System administrator of the IT infrastructure of the company and support its Internet presence.

2017 – 2019 Management consultant at "Engineering Culture in the Management of the Future

Sofia, Bulgaria Foundation".

Positions and activities: Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Development of presentations of the company, acquiring new investors; Project management; System administrator of the IT infrastructure of the company.

2011 – 2017 Management consultant at "Trivium AD".

Yambol, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Project management; Development of training programs and executive of trainings of the personal of the customers.

2007 – 2011 Production engineer and technologist, at "Hydraulic Elements and Systems AD".

Yambol, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Production engineer, team leader, project manager, chief technologist of the metal-cutting processes with CNC machines.

2006 – 2007 Technologist at "Teximp S.A. branch Bulgaria".

Sofia, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Technologist, technical consultant, warehouse manager; service team coordinator.

2004 – 2006 Associate in the Laboratory of Mechanical Engineering Technology, at "Technical University *Sofia, Bulgaria* of Sofia".



Experience relevant to the position

For the past six years I have been undertaking the job of a system administrator for my former employers. This required me to learn how to setup and maintain Linux server, deploy and manage different CMS, and setup and manage Microsoft 365 for a small company.

At present I continue to maintain my former employer's production server, which serves to the Internet several WordPress and MediaWiki sites. During the past year I've also deployed similar services for other partner companies we've worked with.

I've been using ProxmoxVE for the past three years as a bare metal hypervisor solution in my home laboratory. I also have extensive experience with cloud providers such as DigitalOcean, Linode and SuperHosting.BG.

Linux Server

- ✓ Installation and setup of GNU/Linux, primary Debian and Debian based distributions as Ubuntu. This includes firewall setup, user management, SSH, Postfix, etc.
- ✓ Deployment, maintenance, and optimization of services such as Apache2, MariaDB, MySQL, PHP-FPM, MediaWiki, NextCloud, OnlyOffice, WordPress, Apache Guacamole, Redis, Elasticsearch, Docker, Linux containers, virtual machines, and others.
- ✓ Tasks automation and backup solutions via shell scripts and custom services.

Web Servers

- ✓ Apache2: HTTP/HTTPS Virtual host setup. Including experience with multitude of modules such as mod Rewrite, mod Proxy, mod Security2, mod Headers, mod Deflate, mod Expires, mod PHP, etc.
- ✓ NGINX: Limited experience, much less than with Apache2.
- ✓ Node.js: Limited experience with HTTP module and Express framework.

Containers and Virtual machines

- ✓ Docker: Creating images and deploying containers, Dockerfile and Docker-compose.
- ✓ LXD/LXC: Creating and maintain local and remote containers.
- ✓ QEMU/KVM: Creating and maintain virtual machines via GUI and CLI interfaces.
- ✓ ProxmoxVE: Full system administration.

Programming Languages and Shell Scripts

- ✓ Shell Scripts: Experience with various tasks, primary with Bash and Dash, and PowerShell to some degree.
- ✓ JavaScript: Several completed courses, Pure JS, OOP, React.js, Node.js, and entry degree of TypeScript.
- ✓ HTML/CSS: Good overall understanding and knowledge, solving various tasks primary related to CMS.
- ✓ PHP: Basic level, creating simple plugins for WordPress and MediaWiki, creating simple custom APIs.
- ✓ SQL: Basic level, administration, and maintenance of MySQL and MariaDB databases.
- ✓ Python: Basic level, solving some hobby tasks.
- ✓ Lua: Basic level, creating modules for MediaWiki.